const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following tests is used to diagnose benign paroxysmal positional vertigo (BPPV)?","answers":[{"option":"Rinne test","bool":false},{"option":"Epley maneuver","bool":false},{"option":"Dix-Hallpike maneuver","bool":true},{"option":"Fistula test","bool":false},{"option":"Romberg test","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following organisms most commonly causes acute suppurative otitis media (ASOM)?","answers":[{"option":"Staphyloccus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Beta-hemolytic streptococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following types of tympanogram is seen in glue ear?","answers":[{"option":"B","bool":true},{"option":"A","bool":false},{"option":"C","bool":false},{"option":"Ac","bool":false},{"option":"Ad","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following investigations is used to differentiate cochlear from retrocochlear hearing loss?","answers":[{"option":"Electrocochleography","bool":false},{"option":"Otoacoustic emissions","bool":true},{"option":"Impedance audiometry","bool":false},{"option":"Brainstem evoked response audiometry","bool":false},{"option":"Pure tone audiometry","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A teenager is brought to the clinic after having hurt himself during a rugby match at school. Examination reveals a fluctuant swelling on his left pinna, where he was hit by the ball. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Furuncle","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Bullous myringitis","bool":false},{"option":"Perichondritis","bool":false},{"option":"Hematoma","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"When performing surgery for mastoiditis, what landmark will be used as the place to start drilling?","answers":[{"option":"MacEwen's triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior meatal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Promontory","bool":false},{"option":"Post-auricular sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Facial recess","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most likely cause of perforation of the bony part of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Septal hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which test involves applying pressure to the external auditory canal to induce nystagmus?","answers":[{"option":"Caloric test","bool":false},{"option":"Weber test","bool":false},{"option":"Fistula test","bool":true},{"option":"Rinne test","bool":false},{"option":"Romberg test","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common presentation of nasopharyngeal cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve palsies","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing loss","bool":false},{"option":"Epistaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical lymphadenopathy","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A young woman comes to the clinic with the complaint of intermittent episodes of vertigo on turning her head to the left. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Psychogenic vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false},{"option":"Meniere disease","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 24-year-old woman comes to the clinic with complaints of severe vertigo and hearing loss for 4 days. She reports having had a similar attack 1 year ago that resolved without medications. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ménière’s disease","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Perilymph fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false},{"option":"Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 37-year-old man presents to the otorhinolaryngology clinic with the complaint of severe pain in his left ear. Examination reveals several vesicles on the tympanic membrane, meatal skin, and concha. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Otomycosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bullous myringitis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster oticus","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Seborrheic otitis externa","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 9-year-old child is brought to your office with complaints of severe itching and pain in his right ear. Examination reveals a wet newspaper-like mass in the external ear. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tubo-tympanic otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Seborrheic otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media with effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Otomycosis","bool":true},{"option":"Eczematous otitis externa","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A man with a history of chronic suppurative otitis media (CSOM) presents with complaints of severe retro-orbital pain, ear discharge, and diplopia on looking laterally.  What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ramsay-Hunt disease","bool":false},{"option":"Gradenigo syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Bezold's abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Bell's palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Frey's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 9-year-old boy had gotten into a fight 4 days ago. He has now developed bilateral nasal obstruction with pain and fever. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Deviated nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Septal hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Septal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Septal abscess","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 25-year-old woman presents to the office with the complaint of nasal obstruction. Examination reveals a foul smell from the nose as well as roomy nasal cavities with greenish crusts. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fungal sinusitis","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophic rhinitis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophic rhinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rhinitis caseosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mucormycosis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Frequency and loudness are two properties of sound. Frequency is measured in hertz (Hz). Which of the following frequency ranges most accurately represents the audible frequency for a human being?","answers":[{"option":"1000 to 10000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"200 to 2000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"100 to 10000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"10 to 1000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"20 to 20000 Hz","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following investigations is always ordered in cases of chronic suppurative otitis media (CSOM)?","answers":[{"option":"Tympanometry","bool":false},{"option":"Brainstem evoked response audiometry","bool":false},{"option":"Examination under microscope","bool":true},{"option":"CT scan temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray mastoid","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"An 8-year-old child is brought to the physician by his parents with complaints of continuous, odorless, and sticky discharge from his left ear. Examination reveals a central perforation of the tympanic membrane. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute suppurative otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Atticoantral chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media with effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Otitic barotrauma","bool":false},{"option":"Tubotympanic chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A patient is found to have right ear subtotal perforation. Which of the following findings will be seen on tuning fork tests?","answers":[{"option":"Weber lateralizes to better ear","bool":false},{"option":"False negative Rinne's for left ear","bool":false},{"option":"Rinne's negative for right ear","bool":true},{"option":"Rinne's negative for left ear","bool":false},{"option":"Rinne's negative for both ears","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"What is the extent of the parapharyngeal space?","answers":[{"option":"Base of the skull to the epiglottis","bool":false},{"option":"Base of skull to lower border of mandible","bool":false},{"option":"Base of the skull to the hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Base of skull to coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Base of skull to diaphragm","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of Ludwig angina?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular sialadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual sialadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Dental infection","bool":true},{"option":"Injuries to oral mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of mandible","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of oroantral fistula formation?","answers":[{"option":"Carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tooth extraction","bool":true},{"option":"Fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Caldwell-Luc operation","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 40-year-old man presents with the complaint of a swelling on the gums for the past 9 months. It is a soft, smooth, reddish mass that bleeds on touch. He uses a hard toothbrush. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Torus","bool":false},{"option":"Solitary fibrous tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pyogenic granuloma","bool":true},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 62-year-old male suffering from glottic squamous cell carcinoma comes to your clinic. Fiber optic direct laryngoscopy (FODL) reveals an exophytic growth on the right vocal cord. The right vocal cord is also fixed and immobile. Lymph nodes of the neck are not palpable. What is the tumor stage based on these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Stage IV A","bool":false},{"option":"Stage IV B","bool":false},{"option":"Stage III","bool":true},{"option":"Stage I","bool":false},{"option":"Stage II","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the gold standard investigation for the diagnosis of sleep apnea?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary function testing","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalometric radiographs","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect laryngoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral soft tissue X-ray of neck","bool":false},{"option":"Polysomnography","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 65-year-old man with a 10-pack-years of smoking history is diagnosed with glottic cancer. Fiber optic direct laryngoscopy (FODL) reveals exophytic growths on both the vocal cords. The vocal cords are mobile. There is no nodal involvement. How will this tumor be classified according to the TNM classification system?","answers":[{"option":"T2 N1 M0 - Stage III","bool":false},{"option":"T3 N1 M0 - Stage III","bool":false},{"option":"T2 N0 M0 - Stage II","bool":false},{"option":"T1 N0 M0 - Stage I","bool":true},{"option":"T1 N2 M0 - Stage IV","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A newborn is brought to the clinic with the complaint of breathing difficulty. Examination reveals floppy aryepiglottic folds and prominent arytenoids. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital laryngeal paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngomalacia","bool":true},{"option":"Laryngo-tracheo-bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Choanal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital laryngeal web","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"What is the incision on the tympanic membrane called?","answers":[{"option":"Mastoidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanoplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Myringoplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanoplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Myringotomy","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 36-year-old female presents to her primary care physician with a complaint of difficulty in opening her mouth for the last 6 months. She has a history of chewing betel nuts for the last 10 years. Examination reveals generalized pale mucosa and fibrosis in the oral cavity with angular cheilitis. She does not have cervical lymphadenopathy. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aphthous ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma of the oral cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Submucosal fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Leukoplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Erythroplakia","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 24-year-old man presents to the clinic with complaints of severe itching and pain in his right ear. He also complains of pain while opening the mouth. Examination reveals a furuncle located anteriorly on the external auditory canal. Which of the following is the most likely causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following fractures is associated with craniofacial dissociation?","answers":[{"option":"Le Fort I","bool":false},{"option":"Le Fort II","bool":false},{"option":"Tripod fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Class 3","bool":false},{"option":"Le Fort III","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following facial fractures is characterized by step deformity of the infraorbital margin?","answers":[{"option":"Naso-orbital","bool":false},{"option":"Le Fort III","bool":false},{"option":"Le Fort I","bool":false},{"option":"Tripod","bool":true},{"option":"Le Fort II","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"'Hot potato voice' is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Peritonsillar abscess","bool":true},{"option":"Retropharyngeal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Parapharyngeal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tonsillitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute adenoiditis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the clinic because of a 1-week history of pain while swallowing and decreased mouth opening. The boy also has an ongoing dental infection. Oral examination reveals that the tongue is lifted upwards and backward. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Quinsy","bool":false},{"option":"Ludwig's angina","bool":true},{"option":"Parotid abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Parapharyngeal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Retropharyngeal abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common presenting feature of glottic cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Halitosis","bool":false},{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false},{"option":"Hoarseness","bool":true},{"option":"Stridor","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngeal obstruction","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 40-year-old woman undergoes a subtotal thyroidectomy. On her fourth postoperative day, her voice appears to be weak and she is unable tor raise her pitch. Laryngeal examination reveals that the right vocal cord is shortened and the glottis is askew. Which of the following nerve injuries is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Unilateral superior laryngeal nerve injury","bool":true},{"option":"Bilateral superior laryngeal nerve injury","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral recurrent laryngeal nerve injury","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral recurrent laryngeal nerve injury","bool":false},{"option":"Combined superior laryngeal and recurrent laryngeal nerve injury","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 50-year-old man presents to the clinic because of a 2-month history of hoarseness. He has a 10 pack-year history of smoking. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy reveals a horseshoe-shaped ulcerative mass on both vocal cords with normal vocal cord mobility. What is the stage of the tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Stage T3","bool":false},{"option":"Stage T1a","bool":false},{"option":"Stage T4a","bool":false},{"option":"Stage T2","bool":false},{"option":"Stage T1b","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which disease is the result of obstruction of the glands on the floor of the mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Apthous ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Ranula","bool":true},{"option":"Ludwig angina","bool":false},{"option":"Sialadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Mucocele","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the site of the antral lavage or proof puncture?","answers":[{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Where is the sinus of Morgagni located?","answers":[{"option":"Between the hyoid bone and the floor of the mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Between the skull base and the apex of the hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Between the skull base and the superior constrictor","bool":true},{"option":"Between the thyropharyngeus and the cricopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Between the palatoglossal arch and the palatopharyngeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 35-year-old man comes to the clinic with the complaint of sweating over the preauricular sinus whenever he chews food. Several months ago, he had undergone a surgery. Which of the following surgical procedures is most likely to have resulted in this complication?","answers":[{"option":"Tonsillectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Radical neck dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Parotidectomy","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 4-year-old girl is brought into the clinic by her mother with the complaint of bilateral hearing loss for the last 6 months. She has also been snoring at night. Otoscopy reveals fluid level with air bubbles in both ears along with dull, bluish, and retracted tympanic membranes. What is the most likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Glue ear (otitis media with effusion)","bool":true},{"option":"Malignant otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Safe type chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Acute suppurative otitis media","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 26-year-old man is having lunch with his friend at a Chinese restaurant when his face suddenly turns blue. He is having trouble breathing and is unable to speak. Which of the following is the most appropriate first-aid management?","answers":[{"option":"Heimlich maneuver","bool":true},{"option":"Chest compressions","bool":false},{"option":"Mouth-to-mouth breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Jaw thrust","bool":false},{"option":"Intubation","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 17-year-old boy is brought to the clinic for the evaluation of recurrent epistaxis and nasal obstruction. Examination reveals a lobulated mass obstructing the left concha. Which of the following is the investigation of choice for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid angiography","bool":false},{"option":"Soft tissue lateral radiograph of nasopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan of the head with contrast","bool":true},{"option":"Flexible endoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment for a T3 tumor of the larynx without nodal involvement?","answers":[{"option":"Conservation surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Total laryngectomy with neck dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Radiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Total laryngectomy without neck dissection","bool":true},{"option":"Endoscopic resection with CO2 laser","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A neonate of one day of age has recurrent cyanosis and breathing difficulty. A mucoid discharge is noted inside the nasal cavity. Doctors suspect an upper respiratory tract infection, but there is no stridor or fever. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal synechia","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral choanal atresia","bool":true},{"option":"Acute epiglottitis","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngomalacia","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral choanal atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A myringotomy is to be performed in an individual with acute suppurative otitis media. Where should the incision be given in the tympanic membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Anteroinferior quadrant","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroinferior quadrant","bool":true},{"option":"Posterosuperior quadrant","bool":false},{"option":"On the tympanic annulus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterosuperior quadrant","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A school van driver presents to the clinic with a 4-month history of paroxysmal sneezing, runny nose, and watery eyes, precipitated by smoke and dust. A diagnosis of allergic rhinitis is made. Which antihistamine would be best for him?","answers":[{"option":"Promethazine","bool":false},{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false},{"option":"Loratadine","bool":true},{"option":"Meclizine","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorpheniramine","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a component of the middle ear cleft?","answers":[{"option":"Stapes","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":true},{"option":"Antrum","bool":false},{"option":"Malleus","bool":false},{"option":"Incus","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"In noise-induced hearing loss, a typical frequency dip occurs at which of the following frequencies?","answers":[{"option":"2000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"1000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"3000 Hz","bool":false},{"option":"4000 Hz","bool":true},{"option":"1500 Hz","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the primary aim of the surgery in chronic suppurative otitis media?","answers":[{"option":"Restore the hearing mechanism","bool":false},{"option":"Preserve hearing","bool":false},{"option":"Make the ear safe","bool":true},{"option":"Repair the perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Prevent the development of cholesteatoma","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following nerves pass through the internal acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Facial and trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial and vestibulocochlear","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal and trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus and trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal and vagus","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following structures forms part of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Palatine process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Body of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Cribriform plate of ethmoid","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal part of palatine bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following surgical approaches is used to reach the frontal sinus in chronic sinusitis?","answers":[{"option":"Antral puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Young operation","bool":false},{"option":"Howarth or Lynch operation","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior meatal antrostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Caldwell–Luc operation","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which is true regarding pre-malignant lesions of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Erythroplakia is 17 times more malignant than leukoplakia","bool":true},{"option":"Leukoplakia is more malignant than erythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukoplakia is a red erythematous patch","bool":false},{"option":"Erythroplakia is more common in males","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral border of tongue is the most common involved site in erythroplakia","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding mucoepidermoid carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"It is treated by radical parotidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"It is aggressive and highly metastatic","bool":false},{"option":"It is more aggressive in major salivary glands","bool":false},{"option":"Greater the mucoid component, the more malignant the tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Greater the epidermoid component, the more malignant the tumor","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following are the parts of the hypopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Postcricoid region and pyriform fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Precricoid region, posterior pharyngeal wall, pyriform fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Postcricoid region, posterior pharyngeal wall, pyriform fossa and posterior 1/3rd tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Precricoid region, posterior pharyngeal wall, pyriform fossa and posterior 1/3rd tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Postcricoid region, posterior pharyngeal wall, pyriform fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 12-year-old girl is brought to the clinic with complaints of sore throat, coughs, low-grade fever, and malaise for 5 days. Upon general inspection, the child looks ill and lethargic. Vital signs show a temperature of 101 °F (37 °C), a heart rate of 88 beats per minute, and a thready pulse. Oral and throat examinations revealed a thick grey membrane adherent on the faucial tonsils and soft palate. A tongue depressor is used to scrape this membrane resulting in bleeding. Lymph nodes in the jugulodigastric region are palpable. A throat swab is taken and sent for culture. What is the best step in the management of this child's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hospitalization, IV fluids, antitoxin, and emergency tonsillectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Antitoxin only in the clinic","bool":false},{"option":"Antitoxin and anti-tetanus serum","bool":false},{"option":"Hospitalization, IV fluids, and antitoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Hospitalization and IV fluids","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A trumpet player presents with hoarseness and a swelling in the neck which increases in size on coughing and on performing the Valsalva maneuver. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aryepiglottic cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Reinke's edema","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal nodule","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngocele","bool":true},{"option":"Adult-onset papilloma","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Killian's dehiscence is a potential weak space for the formation of the pharyngeal pouch. Where is it found?","answers":[{"option":"Between the upper and lower borders of the cricoid lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Between the base of the skull and the superior constrictor muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Between the thyropharyngeus and cricopharyngeus muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Between the glottic and epiglottic folds","bool":false},{"option":"Between the palatoglossal and palatopharyngeal arches","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 40-year-old man has a cystic, fluctuant mass of bluish color on the inner side of his lower lip. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucocele","bool":true},{"option":"Papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Dermoid","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Ranula","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"An 18-year-old boy presents to the emergency room bleeding profusely from the front of his nose. Bleeding does not stop on pinching the nose for five minutes. The site of the bleed cannot be localized. Which of the following should be the next step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior nasal packing","bool":false},{"option":"Submucosal resection","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior nasal packing","bool":true},{"option":"Ligation of maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Endoscopic cautery","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"The endolymph is rich in which of the following ions?","answers":[{"option":"K+","bool":true},{"option":"HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Ca++","bool":false},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 45-year-old woman who was previously diagnosed with iron deficiency anemia now complains of difficulty in swallowing. What is the most probably diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nutcracker esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Patterson-Brown-Kelly Syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiac achalasia","bool":false},{"option":"Scleroderma","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 65-year-old woman comes to the clinic with a 2-month history of difficulty in swallowing after taking 2-3 bites. She also complains of hearing a gurgling sound on swallowing and regurgitation of food contents at night. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reinke edema","bool":false},{"option":"Plummer-Vinson syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Eagle syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Zenker diverticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A barium swallow study is used for the evaluation of which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Laryngeal pralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Small bowel obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Colorectal disease","bool":false},{"option":"Intraluminal esophageal disease","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions are included in the triad of Behcet disease?","answers":[{"option":"Conjunctivitis, urethritis, and arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"External rectus palsy, retro-orbital pain, and persistent ear discharge.","bool":false},{"option":"Mouth ulcers, genital ulcerations, and uveitis","bool":true},{"option":"Facial paralysis, swelling of lips, and fissured tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia, iron-deficiency anemia, and esophageal webs","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following structures forms the promontory in the middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Apical coil of the cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the incus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal coil of the cochlea","bool":true},{"option":"Bulge of the petrous bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral process of the malleus","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"What is the normal constituent of the mastoid antrum?","answers":[{"option":"Endolymph","bool":false},{"option":"Wax","bool":false},{"option":"Water","bool":false},{"option":"Air cells","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 16-year-old boy is brought to the clinic for the evaluation of recurrent, bilateral profuse epistaxis and nasal obstruction. There is no history of recent trauma. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Juvenile nasopharyngeal angiofibroma","bool":true},{"option":"Septal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharyngeal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Deviated nasal septum","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 25-year-old Caucasian woman comes to the clinic for evaluation of bilateral, conductive, complete deafness, which started as decreased hearing a year ago and got worse during her pregnancy. There is no history of ear discharge, but she complains of ringing in the ears occasionally. Her brother has also suffered from the same problem for 3 years. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media with effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Ménière’s disease","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyacusis","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following vertebral levels is the most common site of lodgement of a swallowed foreign body?","answers":[{"option":"C6","bool":true},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"T4","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of acute follicular tonsillitis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding sinonasal polyps?","answers":[{"option":"Ethmoidal polyp are multiple and bilateral","bool":true},{"option":"Ethmoidal polyp are common in children","bool":false},{"option":"Caldwell-Luc's operation is used to treat them","bool":false},{"option":"Antrochoanal polyp have 2 parts","bool":false},{"option":"Allergy may cause an antrochoanal polyp","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the surface anatomy of the hypopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve runs in pyriform fossa","bool":false},{"option":"It has three parts; pre-cricoid region, posterior wall and pyriform fossa","bool":false},{"option":"It lies opposite the C3-C4 vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"It extends from the hyoid bone to the level of cricoarytenoid joint","bool":true},{"option":"It is the middle part of pharynx","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is the gold standard investigation for detecting the site of defect in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) rhinorrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) cisternography","bool":true},{"option":"Intrathecal fluorescein study","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal endoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding the bony labyrinth?","answers":[{"option":"It contains three compartments; scala vestibuli, scala media, and scala tympani","bool":true},{"option":"Bony cochlea winds around pyramid of bone called modiolus","bool":false},{"option":"It consists of the vestibule, the semicircular canals and the cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Three semicircular canals open into the vestibule by five openings","bool":false},{"option":"The central chamber is vestibule","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"Which of the following instruments can be used for the removal of a foreign body from the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Tilley's forceps","bool":true},{"option":"Luc’s forceps","bool":false},{"option":"Sickle knife","bool":false},{"option":"Wilde’s dressing forceps","bool":false},{"option":"Lempert’s curette","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/ent/2019","question":"A 60-year-old man presents with stridor secondary to laryngeal carcinoma. He has a history of chronic smoking for the past 30 years. Which of the following types of tracheostomy would be indicated in this case?","answers":[{"option":"High tracheostomy","bool":true},{"option":"Dilatational tracheostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Mid tracheostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Mini tracheostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Low tracheostomy","bool":false}]}]
export default arr